Anton Agejev

Address: Hampton, London

Mobile: +447554000472 **Email:** aenrua@gmail.com **Portfolio:** https://aenrua.github.io/Portfolio/

Personal Profile

I have a BSc in Observational Astronomy, an MSc in Science, Media and Communication, and professional experience in developing Metrology classroom-based and e-learning courses.

A highly motivated, ambitious, approachable and friendly person, I am currently looking to resume my professional career after taking a career break and retraining in Software Development.

Over the next several years, I am looking to gain experience within the IT industry and further develop my coding skills.

IT Skills

Software Development Skills: VS Code, MySQL, Python, Lua

Web Technology: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, WordPress, GitHub, Replit

Core Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python

Projects: JavaScript location-based weather web app, Python command line database management app, Python turtle simulation with matplotlib pyplot graph

Education and IT Training

12/2023-Present Just IT Training Ltd, Lor	ndon
---	------

Digital Skills Bootcamp: Software Development

An intensive twelve-week bootcamp covering the fundamentals of Web and Software development. I joined this bootcamp after creating a blog about my travels during my career break. I enjoyed working on it so much that I decided to pursue a career in IT. This bootcamp gave me the necessary skills that allow me to create and develop applications using different languages, including HTML, CSS,

JavaScript and Python

09/2016-09/2017 Cardiff University, Cardiff

MSc Science, Media and Communication

Core Modules: International News Production; Media, Science and Health;

Introduction to Science, Technology and Society; Principles and Practice of Research; Public Engagement with Science and

Technology; Presenting Science

Final Year Project: "What do scientific discoveries mean to the general public?"

An investigation of how important 2 major scientific discoveries were to the general public, and the role of the media in shaping

the public's understanding

09/2013-06/2016 University of South Wales, Treforest

BSc Observational Astronomy

Core Modules: Astrobiology; Astronomical Techniques; Astrophysics;

Communicating Science; Cosmology; Education in Schools; Exploring

the Sky; Geophysics; History of Astronomy; Planetary Science;

Quanta, Particles and Relativity; Sun and Stars

Final Year Project: "Contacting and Communicating with Extra-terrestrials"

Examination of literature sources to identify the most suitable method of searching for and communicating with extra-terrestrials

09/2011-06/2013 The Downs School Sixth Form, Compton

A Level: Media Studies (C) ICT (D) Applied Science (D) Russian (12)

09/2006-06/2011 The Downs School, Compton

GCSE: 7 A*-C grades in subjects including Maths and English

Employment History

06/2022-12/2023 Career break

- Travelling around the world to explore and immerse myself in other cultures
- Solo backpacking around Greece, visiting historic archaeological sites and ruins
- Living in Estonia and helping my father build his ship engine repair business, both online and hands-on in the workshop
- Undertaking physical training to improve my health and fitness, and developing myself as a person

10/2017-06/2022 National Physical Laboratory, Teddington Junior Science Writer/E-learning Developer

- Understanding and translating complex scientific information, theories and practices into clear, concise and accurate written content tailored to a variety of target audiences
- Working with scientists to gain subject expert input and knowledge regarding the courses that we were designing
- Creating graphics for classrooms and e-learning platforms using Microsoft Office PowerPoint,
 GIMP, Inkscape and PhotoScape
- Designing, creating and scripting e-learning content using the Adapt authoring tool
- Collaborating with team members to complete projects, including breaking down projects into smaller tasks and setting deadlines
- Taking lead in e-learning developing and teaching other team members new methods of improving the user interface and interactivity through CSS coding
- Adding LaTeX code to e-learning courses to display scientific equations in browsers
- Creating and editing videos for e-learning platforms in Camtasia, uploading videos to Vimeo, and scripting and inserting closed captions
- Designing the course pages on Moodle and uploading the completed SCORM packages

09/2016-07/2017 Cardiff and County Club, Cardiff Waiter/Barman

- Looking after front of house, welcoming customers and providing excellent customer service
- Working behind the bar and serving customers food and drink in an extremely fast-paced environment
- Working with the kitchen staff to ensure orders were delivered in a timely manner
- Handling money and operating the till

04/2013-08/2013 Nando's, Newbury Waiter/Cashier

- Part of the waiting and till team
- Taking customer orders, bringing food to the tables, and clearing and restocking items
- Developed money handling, till training, and multitasking skills

04/2012-02/2013 Mercure Hotels, Newbury Waiter

• Part of the waiting team in the restaurant section of the hotel

• Looking after the restaurant and buffet area, working behind the bar, providing room service, and serving at weddings and corporate events

Interests and Achievements

Computing: Well versed in computers, from understanding hardware and how it works, to the backend administration side of Windows. I have built my own desktop PC and continue to enhance my skills in managing and fixing any system issues that arise. Through this, I am self-taught in Windows commands and have a good understanding of Windows infrastructure. Having enjoyed working in elearning development at NPL, I undertook Codecademy and Udemy courses in HTML and CSS to further develop my skills

Hobbies:

- Acting Avid actor and have performed in a variety of theatre shows since 2019. When theatres
 were closed during COVID-19, I took part in radio/online performances and performed at a
 singing showcase in 2021
- **Astrophotography** Got into taking pictures of the night sky during my undergraduate study, using a DSLR camera and remote telescopes in Hawaii and Australia. Proficient in Adobe Photoshop and Premiere Pro, and some experience with InDesign
- Sports Enjoy a variety of sports such as snowboarding, ice-climbing, volleyball and hiking.
 During the second and third years of my undergraduate study, I was the captain of the volleyball team

Additional Info:

- BBC Sky at Night Magazine: During my MSc in Cardiff, I had the opportunity to work for BBC Sky
 at Night Magazine for a week in Bristol, writing astronomy news, engaging with audiences on
 social media, and creating an online feature article. This allowed me to gain knowledge of how
 magazines are run and gave me valuable experience in writing science news online and
 interacting with audiences on social media
- STEM Outreach: In my final year of my undergraduate degree, I became a STEM Ambassador and have gone into different primary schools around Wales to conduct science lessons. This has involved working with teachers to create and teach engaging lessons, and communicate complex, technical ideas in a way the children would understand. I continued to be a STEM ambassador in London until 2021, taking part in several outreach activities whilst working at NPL
- Army Reserves: Whilst studying at University I also served in the Army Reserves as an Infantry
 soldier where I attended drill nights weekly, and exercise weekends monthly. Additionally, I also
 went away on military training courses that varied between 1-3 weeks in length, and completed
 Basic Training. This was a highly valuable experience that improved my teamwork, personal
 discipline and problem-solving skills

References available upon request